teamer.net 2019-06-08

# Privacy Policy

Beamax Limited understands that your privacy is important to you and that you care about how your personal data is used. We respect and value the privacy of our members and will only collect and use personal data in ways that are described here, and in a way that is consistent with our obligations and your rights under the law.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and ensure that you understand it. Your acceptance of this Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of Teamer. If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Teamer immediately.

## **1\. DEFINITIONS AND INTERPRETATION**

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:

**Account** \- means an account required to access and/or use certain areas and features of Teamer

**Cookie** \- means a small text file placed on your computer or device by Teamer when you visit certain parts of Teamer and/or when you use certain features of Teamer. Details of the Cookies used by Teamer are set out in Part 14, below; and  
 **Cookie Law** \- means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003;

## **2\. INFORMATION ABOUT US**

Teamer is owned and operated by Beamax Limited, a limited company registered in Ireland under company number 445200.  
Registered address: 88 Harcourt Street, Dublin 2, Ireland.   
Email address: help@teamer.net

## **3\. WHAT DOES THIS POLICY COVER?**

This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Teamer. Teamer may contain links to other websites. Please note that we have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

## **4\. WHAT IS PERSONAL DATA?**

Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679) (the “GDPR”) as ‘any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier’.

Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data, and other online identifiers.

## **5\. WHAT ARE MY RIGHTS?**

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

  1. The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy Policy should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions using the details in Part 15.
  2. The right to access the personal data we hold about you. Part 13 will tell you how to do this.
  3. The right to have your personal data rectified if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete. Please contact us using the details in Part 15 to find out more.
  4. The right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we have. Please contact us using the details in Part 15 to find out more.
  5. The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.
  6. The right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes.
  7. The right to data portability. This means that, if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract, and that data is processed using automated means, you can ask us for a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases.
  8. Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling. [we do not use your personal data in this way.]

For more information about our use of your personal data or exercising your rights as outlined above, please contact us using the details provided in Part 15. 

## **6\. WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT?**

Depending upon your use of Teamer, we may collect some or all of the following personal [and non-personal] data (please also see Part 14 on our use of Cookies and similar technologies and our [Cookie Policy](https://teamerstg.net/privacy#1):

  * Name;
  * Date of birth;
  * Gender;
  * Email address;
  * Telephone number;
  * Club/Team name;
  * Club address;
  * Information about your sports interests;
  * IP address;
  * Web browser type and version;
  * Operating system;
  * A list of URLs starting with a referring site, your activity on Teamer, and the site you exit to;

## **7\. HOW DO YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA?**

Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. Your personal data may be used for one of the following purposes:

  * Providing and managing your Account;
  * Providing and managing your access to Teamer;
  * Personalising and tailoring your experience on Teamer;
  * Supplying our services to you. Your personal details are required in order for us to enter into a contract with you.
  * Personalising and tailoring our services for you.
  * Communicating with you. This may include responding to emails or calls from you.
  * Supplying you with information by email, SMS or Push Notification that you have opted-in to (you may unsubscribe or opt-out at any time.
  * Analysing your use of Teamer and gathering feedback to enable us to continually improve Teamer and your user experience.

With your permission and/or where permitted by law, we may also use your personal data for marketing purposes, which may include contacting you by email or telephone with information, news, and offers on our products and services. You will not be sent any unlawful marketing or spam. we will always work to fully protect your rights and comply with our obligations under the GDPR and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003, and you will always have the opportunity to opt-out.

Third Parties whose content appears on Teamer may use third-party Cookies, as detailed below in Part 14. Please refer to Part 14 for more information on controlling cookies. Please note that we do not control the activities of such third parties, nor the data that they collect and use themselves, and we advise you to check the privacy policies of any such third parties.

## **8\. HOW LONG WILL YOU KEEP MY PERSONAL DATA?**

We will not keep your personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected.

## **9\. HOW AND WHERE DO YOU STORE OR TRANSFER MY PERSONAL DATA?**

We may store or transfer some or all of your personal data in countries that are not part of the European Economic Area (the “EEA” consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). These are known as “third countries” and may not have data protection laws that are as strong as those in the UK and/or the EEA. This means that we will take additional steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the UK and under the GDPR as follows.

We share your data within the group of companies of which we are a part. Where this involves the transfer of personal data outside the EEA, our group ensures that personal data is protected by requiring all companies within the group to follow the same rules with respect to personal data usage. These are known as “binding corporate rules”. More information on binding corporate rules is available from the European Commission.

The security of your personal data is essential to us, and to protect your data, we take a number of important measures, including the following:

  * We ensure that all password information is encrypted using SHA-256 level encryption.
  * The entire Teamer application uses SSL to ensure that data is captured and stored securely.
  * We use SSH key pair authentication to ensure that only specific staff machines can access our database.
  * Any device without the correct SSH key that tries to access our database will be rejected and the sending IP address is blocked.

## **10\. DO YOU SHARE MY PERSONAL DATA?**

We may share your personal data with other companies in our group for legitimate business purposes. This includes subsidiaries.

We may sometimes contract with the following third parties to supply certain products or services. These may include payment processing, ad delivery, and marketing. In some cases, those third parties may require access to some or all of your personal data that we hold.

  * Hubspot - Customer management
  * Google - Ad delivery and analytics
  * Zendesk - Customer support
  * Stripe - Payments processing

If any of your personal data is required by a third party, as described above, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data is handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, our obligations, and the third party’s obligations under the law, as described above in Part 9.

If any personal data is transferred outside of the EEA, we will take suitable steps in order to ensure that your personal data is treated just as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the GDPR, as explained above in Part 9.

In some limited circumstances, we may be legally required to share certain personal data, which might include yours, if we are involved in legal proceedings or complying with legal obligations, a court order, or the instructions of a government authority.

## **11\. HOW CAN I CONTROL MY PERSONAL DATA?**

In addition to your rights under the GDPR, set out in Part 5, when you submit personal data via Teamer, you may be given options to restrict our use of your personal data. In particular, we aim to give you strong controls on our use of your data for direct marketing purposes (including the ability to opt-out of receiving emails from us which you may do by unsubscribing using the links provided in our emails.

## **12\. CAN I WITHHOLD INFORMATION?**

You may access certain areas of Teamer without providing any personal data at all. However, to use all features and functions available on Teamer you may be required to submit or allow for the collection of certain data.

You may restrict our use of Cookies. For more information, see our [Cookie Policy](https://teamerstg.net/privacy#1).

## **13\. HOW CAN I ACCESS MY PERSONAL DATA?**

If you want to know what personal data we have about you, you can ask us for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the email or postal addresses shown in Part 15. [To make this as easy as possible for you, a Subject Access Request Form is available for you to use. You do not have to use this form, but it is the easiest way to tell us everything we need to know to respond to your request as quickly as possible.]

There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is ‘manifestly unfounded or excessive’ (for example, if you make repetitive requests) a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within 14 days and, in any case, not more than one month of receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request. You will be kept fully informed of our progress.

## **14\. HOW DO YOU USE COOKIES?**

Teamer may place and access certain first-party Cookies on your computer or device. First-party Cookies are those placed directly by us and are used only by us. We use Cookies to facilitate and improve your experience of Teamer and to provide and improve our products and services.

By using Teamer you may also receive certain third-party Cookies on your computer or device. Third-party Cookies are those placed by websites, services, and/or parties other than us. Third-party Cookies are used on Teamer for personalising your experience including the advertisements that you may see.

In addition, Teamer uses analytics services, which also use Cookies. Website analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse usage statistics, enabling us to better understand how people use Teamer.

**EU Cookie Directive - Web legislation Notification**

The EU cookie directive notice appears on the Teamer site to inform EU members that Teamer stores cookies on your computer. We operate an implied consent approach, whereby we inform users that we are using cookies and if they continue to use Teamer, they are giving their consent for us to store cookies on their machine. If they do not wish to have cookies stored on their machine, we ask that they no longer use Teamer as cookies are important part of delivering a great browsing experience for our users.

Once you have clicked through to our Privacy Policy or click the 'x' to close the EU Cookie Directive notice, it will not be shown again.

* * *

What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that are placed on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

How are cookies used on Teamer?

We and our authorized third party partners may use cookies, to deliver more relevant content to our members.   
Cookies perform important and useful functions: 

  * they make it possible to provide personalized pages for visitors;
  * they help advertisers avoid repeatedly serving the same ads to the same visitor;
  * they help website owners determine which sections of their sites are more appealing;

What is device identification?

Device Identification is a technology that identifies devices by collecting information from the browser on the device, such as the browser version, operating system, IP address, installed fonts, time zone and more. These pieces of information are used to uniquely identify a device. This process does not use any personal information. The device ID generated through the device identification process may be stored in a cookie.

What are the different types of cookies?

First-party cookies are those set by Teamer to improve your user experience. They enable us to log you in automatically if you have set your login status to 'remember me'. They also enable us to provide you with personalized Teampage information and ensure that we only show you information that is relevant to members in your country.

Examples of First-party cookies on Teamer are:

  * user_credentials, used to bypass login, if you have selected to do so
  * _teamer_session, stores important information that enables us to provide a personalized browsing experience, ensuring you only see Teamer content relevant to your user account.

Third-party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than that of the website being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and another entity sets a cookie through that website this would be a third-party cookie.

Examples of third-party cookies used on Teamer are:

  * __qca - set by quantcast, this enables us to ensure we are serving relevant ads to Teamer members.
  * __gads - set by Google, also ensures that the correct ads are shown to Teamer members.
  * __utma, __utmb, __utmc, __utmz set by Google Analytics, Teamer uses Google Analytics to learn important information about where our site traffic comes from. This includes information like a site visitor's location, the type of browser being used, the type of device someone is using to access Teamer, whether or not someone is a new visitor.

**NOTE: Non of our third party cookies disclose any personal information about a user. The statistics are collected anonymously.**

How to delete and block our cookies?

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon you visit our site. Turning off or deleting cookies will not prevent device identification and related data collection from occurring, but it will prevent you from being able to login automatically to your teampage and also ensure a personalized browsing experience on Teamer. 

Can I withdraw my consent?

If you do not wish to have Teamer cookies stored on your machine, you will need to delete your cookies using your internet browser settings. For further information about deleting or blocking cookies, please visit: http://www.aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2.

## **15\. HOW DO I CONTACT YOU?**

To contact us about anything to do with your personal data and data protection, including to make a subject access request, please use the following details: 

Email address: help@teamer.net

## **16\. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We may change this Privacy Notice from time to time. This may be necessary, for example, if the law changes, or if we change our business in a way that affects personal data protection.

Any changes will be posted on Teamer and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Teamer following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
